Ryan S. Brown

Contact

2554 Nathaniel Rochester Hall Rochester, NY 14623

(323) 761-9146 sb@ryansb.com

Summary

I love working with large systems, the less predictable the better. Building a system that may have to deal with fifteen times the traffic or multiple failures is my favorite kind of project. My free time quickly fills with personal projects and time spent researching new tools or areas of my field.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

September 2009 - Present

• Major: B.S. Applied Networking and Systems Administration

• GPA: 3.4

Minor: Software Engineering Expected graduation: May 2013

EXPERIENCE

RIT Lab for Technological Literacy - Rochester, NY

System Administrator

August 2012 - Present http://foss.rit.edu/

Worked as a System Administrator in the Free and Open Source Software initiative under the Lab For Technological Literacy. Maintained user-facing web applications and services while configuring new ones.

Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

August 2011 - Present http://reslife.rit.edu/

Resident Advisor

Mentored and supervised 55 co-ed students ranging from first to fifth year. My duties also included planning and hosting community building events, enforcing policies, and resolving conflicts between residents.

Google - Pittsburgh, PA Software Engineer Intern June 2012 - August 2012 http://google.com/

Wrote infrastructure management software in Python and C++. This required that I gain a deep familiarity with Google compute resources and infrastructure to understand the project scope. The software managed requests for maintenance-related downtime and scheduled them as to not interfere with running services or unnecessarily impact redundancy.

Cypherworx, Inc. - Fairport, NY Cloud Infrastructure Consultant

March 2012 - June 2012 http://cypherworx.com/

Cypherworx needed a more scaleable infrastructure to cope with a growing user base. I worked with them to design an infrastructure on Rackspace that would grow with them. I wrote maintenance scripts for the new instances in Bash and Python, as well as tools to move existing content Rackspace's CDN without changing existing workflows.

Newstex, LLC - Telecommute Application Support Engineer March 2011 - March 2012

http://newstex.com/

Wrote WSGI applications to deliver news stories to users. Newstex was an entirely AWS environment, and I wrote applications that interacted with EC2, S3, SQS, Route53, and SDB. My primary role was the design and implementation of RESTful API's that were part of a set of internal tools that parsed HTML/XHTML/XML with absolutely minimal delay.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python, C++, Perl, Java, Bash, PHP, SASS/CSS

Platforms Linux [RHEL, CentOS, Debian], Windows Server [2008, 2003], Z/OS [Z9, Z10]

Services Kerberos, BIND, DHCPD, Apache, NginX, Jabber

Tools Vim, Git, Mercurial, Regex, Make, Nose, LATEX

PROJECTS

Boto: Contributed to the open-source Python interface to Amazon Web Services, added support for uploading and executing scripts automatically on new instances.

IMPULSE Shell: Wrote a Python shell to interface to IMPULSE, a PgSQL-backed application to manage DNS, DHCP, and machine registration. The shell allowed users to interactively make changes in the PgSQL backend their devices, addresses, and DNS records.

http://github.com/ryansb/ish/